GUILHERME SILVA PORTO

Data Analyst Entry Level

#+5571 999136989 engguilhermeporto@gmail.com

#https://github.com/GuilhermePort0/Sanitation_Data_Wordwide



SUMMARY

Hello, I'm Guilherme S. Porto, 25, and I live in Brazil. I'm a Mechanical Engineering student who got involved in data analysis during university and I was hooked by the field. Started my data analysis career doing research in a reliability and risk management group focused on concrete-mixer trucks 5 years ago and since then I never stopped working with data analysis.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Free Lancer

~ 2017 - Ongoing+ Salvador, BA, Brazil

I work mostly in the mechanical and electrical engineering fields, developing products and bringing solutions through EDA. My work consists of data gathering, technological route analysis, consulting for product development and data driven recommendations.

Intern

CEC Engenharia LTDA

~ 08/2020 - 09/2021+

Salvador, BA, Brazil

Industrial piping systems projects

Responsible for registering, buying and managing equipment for different industries, in this position I also implemented a unified system of purchase control for multiple collaborators, ensuring easy access of information; Also elaborated the scope of work for different projects, and gathered information in different databases such as SAP and workspace.

Researcher

Catholic University of Salvador - UCSAL

~ 07/2017 - 07/2020+ Salvador, B

Educational institution of advanced learning

Academic Researcher of the Reliability and Risk Management department of the Catholic University of Salvador, working as a data analyst and article developer.

FIND ME ONLINE

https://www.linkedin.co m/in/guilherme-porto 6babba186/

PASSIONS

Running Learning

SKILLS

Data Analysis, Tableau, R

Power BI, Excel/Google Sheets,

SQL, SAP: MM, PM, PP

Detail oriented, Communicative

Proactive, Creative

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering

Catholic University of Salvador - UCSAL ~ 2016 -

Ongoing+, 8th semester Salvador, Ba

Data Analyst Professional Certificate

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

~ 08/2021 - 01/2022+ , Graduated. Coursera

Scrum

Mind Master Agile training

~ 01/2022 - Ongoing+ Online

LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native

English Fluent

Spanish Intermediate